{
    "id": "a6ae3cca8898463a9c1a786188c02f0d",
    "title": "Gap Filling Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "Janet as well as her sisters …………………… well.",
            "description": "When we connect two nouns with as well as, the verb agrees with the former. ",
            "answers": [
                "sing",
                "sings",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "…………………… she is very rich, she is not very happy.",
            "description": "As and since give the reason. Though is used to connect two contrasting ideas. ",
            "answers": [
                "Though",
                "As",
                "Since"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "When we were kids, we …………………….. go swimming every weekend.",
            "description": "Both would and used to can be used to talk about past habits. ",
            "answers": [
                "will go",
                "would",
                "used to"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The sun as well as the moon …………………….. light.",
            "description": "When we connect two nouns with as well as, the verb agrees with the former. ",
            "answers": [
                "give",
                "gives"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She screamed ……………………… she was in pain.",
            "description": "As if and as though are used to say what a situation seems like. ",
            "answers": [
                "though",
                "as if",
                "as though"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "…………………… he was very arrogant, no one liked him.",
            "description": "As shows the reason.",
            "answers": [
                "As",
                "Though",
                "If"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He is ………………………. to buy a yacht.",
            "description": "When enough is an adverb, it goes after the adjective or adverb modified by it.",
            "answers": [
                "rich enough",
                "enough rich"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He was ……………………. tired to walk.",
            "description": "Note the pattern too..to..",
            "answers": [
                "so",
                "too",
                "very"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "It is time you ……………………… another place to live in.",
            "description": "A past tense is used after it is time...",
            "answers": [
                "find",
                "found",
                "have found"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The house was ……………………. beautiful that he decided to buy it.",
            "description": "Note the conjunction so...that...",
            "answers": [
                "very",
                "so",
                "too"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "If you had been careful, the accident …………………………",
            "description": "In the third conditional, we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would have + past participle in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will not happen",
                "would not happen",
                "would not have happened"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "If you are free in the afternoon, we ………………………. to the movies.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, we use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will/can/may + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "can go",
                "could go",
                "could have gone"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        }
    ]
}